WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
(SIGHS)
You'll never guess
what's happened now.
Mrs Bute's been taken ill and
she won't be back again for weeks.
What does that mean? They want me in
London to take over
and they've asked for you
to go with me.
I thought they only needed us
to help with Lady Rose's ball.
The plans have changed,
so you're coming with me
and Ivy can stay to cook
for Mr Branson and Lady Edith.
Why does Lady Edith look so tired?
She goes away for eight months
to Geneva and comes back looking
more tired than when she left.
We're all tired.
We're not as tired
as we're going to be.
I might go with them. I must look
into Michael's office now I'm back.
Come with me.
No. I have things to do.
Don't imagine for one minute
you can get out of the ball.
Why wasn't Grantham House sold
when Downton was in trouble?
It would have been, eventually, but
not for nearly enough to save us.
So thank God for Matthew.
Dear Matthew.
I do miss him.
Are you looking forward to it?
Why would I be?
What difference does it make
if you peel potatoes in London
or peel them in Yorkshire?
Huh!
Can you do me a favour
when you're in London?
Tell Miss Baxter that I'm looking
forward to hearing the stories
she's got to tell me.
That's an odd message. What stories?
Just tell her. She'll understand.
I'm going up on Tuesday. Robert's
got me invited to the supper
after the presentation.
Lucky you. When are you going
to London? Tomorrow, I think.
I must get some clothes
now I'm back to normal shape.
I...
I know we never talk about the baby.
But I realise it must be
on your mind constantly.
Can we please say she and not "it"?
I wish you hadn't been away so long.
They thought it helps the baby,
to be weaned by her real mother.
Yes. Well, I'm sure everything
worked out for the best.
After all,
your French must be "superbe"!
That's right, Granny. Let's get back
to what really matters.
Do we have to go to this?
Of course we do.
If Lady Wimborne gives
a concert and a dinner,
then we should be grateful.
When does the American contingent
arrive?
And how on earth
are we going to manage them?
Don't be ashamed of my mother.
She's your grandmother.
It's very kind of them
to come over for my ball.
You haven't met her yet.
And where will everyone sleep?
This place isn't designed
for house parties. We'll manage.
Perhaps you could share with Edith?
You're joking?
Well, someone may have to sleep on
the top floor, with the servants.
I'd rather sleep on the roof
than share with Edith.
Come on, we're going to be late.
Carson, all this kerfuffle is making
a lot of extra work for the staff,
so I'd like you to plan some sort of
outing for them after the ball,
before we go home.
Very good, Your Ladyship.
Oh, by they way, Madeleine Allsopp
asked if I'd go on
to the Embassy afterwards.
Tonight, after the dinner?
You don't mind, do you?
Rose, once we get past Tuesday -
I don't think you have to be
presented to go to the Embassy Club.
I do love Ambrose And His Orchestra.
Please!
Your niece is a flapper. Accept it.
I'm not a flapper.
But can I go?
Lord Merton, madam. Oh, golly!
Have I forgotten some plan?
No, no. I'm on my way
to dine with the Scroops
and I'm early.
I was driving through the village.
Thank goodness.
I thought I might have to rush
upstairs and bedeck myself out
in family jewels.
After 30 years with Lady Merton,
I'm proof against teasing.
I'm sorry about my humble soup.
Is there anything I can offer you?
No, thank you.
I just wondered if you were going
to Rose's ball?
I'm invited but I doubt it.
Pity. I thought if you were,
I'd make up my mind to go too.
A debutante's ball in high society
is not really my natural habitat,
Lord Merton.
I'm much duller and more serieuse
than you seem to think.
You may be serieuse,
the rest I would question.
Enough. I leave you to the delights
of your soup.
(JAZZ BAND PLAYING)
Where? Oh, there they are.
Oh, no. What is it? There's my father
and he's seen me.
I think it's rather wild to find
your father in a nightclub.
You wouldn't if it were
a weekly occurrence.
Can't we just wave hello and leave
it at that?
Don't you see whom he's with?
The Prince of Wales!
Your Royal Highness, may I present
my daughter, Madeleine?
Mrs Dudley Ward,
my daughter, Madeleine.
And this is...?
Lady Rose MacClare.
Your father must be Shrimpie
Flintshire. He is, Your Royal
Highness. Good old Shrimpie.
Won't you join us?
We'd be honoured, sir.
How's old Shrimpie getting on?
Pretty well, I think.
Do you know, he put me up in Bombay
last year when I was touring India?
He wrote and told me all about it.
Your visit was a great honour.
I don't know about that.
He was very hospitable.
But I'm afraid I found it
so beastly hot.
How in the name of blazes
does he stand it?
I'm not sure he has much choice
in the matter, sir.
No, indeed.
No choice at all, poor devil.
I can't tell you how pleased I am
to have some reinforcements.
He was rather grouchy. Now look
what a difference you've made.
Have you got everything, Daisy?
I think so.
Well, good luck, then.
I'll see you in London.
Goodbye.
Any orders for Ivy, sir?
Something simple for lunch.
But I'll go down to the pub
for my dinner.
I don't want to make any trouble.
Hello! What brings you here?
I hope to give Mary lunch
and take her to the viewing
of the Summer Exhibition.
It's a special one, isn't it?
My niece is going.
What a nice surprise for Mary.
It's not quite a surprise.
We arranged it last week.
What's all this?
Things for Rose. They didn't dare
take them down the service steps.
Some people have all the luck.
Make sure you're back in time
for Grandmama. (SIGHS)
Does Mr Branson want anything else?
He says not.
And he's having his dinner
in the village.
Marvellous, isn't it?
One minute he's the chauffeur,
and in the normal way of things,
he'd be below me now.
But instead I have to wait on him
hand and foot,
standing there while he decides
what might please him next.
He never strikes me
as being like that.
He always seems friendly.
But we still have to call him sir.
Oh, Lord, Mrs Levinson's arrived.
Who's that man with the fur collar?
That must be Her Ladyship's brother.
Help me get everything down
and don't make a noise.
Mr Start will give us a hand.
Grandmama, you're here already.
Mama said you were coming later.
Obviously she thought so,
as did everyone else.
Carson tells me there's no-one
in the house to receive me.
Well, I'm here now.
How was your journey?
How would it be
when my maid turned in her notice
just as we were leaving?
Why? Who knows why these people do
what they do.
Carson, can we help? Shall we let
Mrs Hughes get inside, My Lady,
and then she can make a plan?
Mrs Hughes, I didn't know you were
running this house too.
Not as a rule, madam,
but Mrs Bute is ill,
so I am to take charge
until she's better.
Well, I'm glad at least one person
under this roof knows
what on earth is going on.
Come on.
You're Uncle Harold, aren't you?
Ah... It seems mad that we've never
met before.
Well, I haven't felt the need
to leave America
and to be honest, I don't feel
the need to leave it now.
Grandmama thought it might be fun
for you to see a bit of the season.
You may not know me but I suspect
you've heard enough to grasp
that watching debutantes in
a ballroom is not my kind of fun.
No, but every now and then it's nice
to try something new, isn't it?
Well, maybe it is
and maybe it ain't.
I'm Jimmy, one of the footmen.
Do you need a hand?
How do you do?
Ethan Slade, valet to Mr Levinson.
What about you? Do you work here?
I work at the house in Yorkshire
but I'm up here for a bit.
Are you a lady's maid?
No, I'm in the kitchen.
Because we're in need of
a lady's maid and pronto,
preferably with skin
like a rhinoceros.
Daisy is our assistant cook
and I'm Mrs Hughes, the house-keeper.
Do you know London? I've never
crossed the Atlantic before.
Well, I hope you enjoy yourself.
Are you excited? I'm never excited.
That boiler sounds as if
it's about to blow up.
Do I hear the sound of salvation?
Salvation or chaos. I've just met
Mrs Levinson on the steps.
She's here without a maid.
What happened to the last one?
She had her head bitten off
one time too many.
Miss Baxter, could you go up
and settle Mrs Levinson in?
I don't mind
but she and Her Ladyship will
have to make allowances.
I don't think making allowances is
what Mrs Levinson is famous for.
Ooh, you're a sight for sore eyes.
We've a dinner tonight
and an at-home after,
so there's plenty to do.
What's an at-home? People pop by
for music and chat and so on.
We serve a light supper at eleven
but we never know for how many,
so we've got to be flexible.
Hello, Mr Molesley.
I hope life's treating you well.
Half the time there's nothing to do,
then it's all hands to the pump
but I don't mind that.
Thomas sent a message. He says he's
looking forward to hearing the
stories you're going to tell him.
What stories? I don't know.
That's what he said.
So what new scheme are you working
on to beat down the upper classes?
You think me much more
of a Robespierre than I am.
Well, I suppose I must accept
that in a post-war world
we toffs are the villains
of every story.
And do you think that's how I feel?
Well, I hope you make exceptions.
Naturally,
I exempt all pig-rescuers. Hmm.
Hello. What's Tony Gillingham doing
here? Talking to Rose, apparently.
You never said you were coming
to this.
Well, I'm glad I have some secrets.
Mary, do you know Mrs Dudley Ward?
My cousin, Lady Mary Crawley.
How did you come across Rose?
We met through Billy Aysgarth.
Madeleine Allsopp's father.
I've asked them both to come
tonight. Have you told Mama?
I will when I get back.
Have you met Charles Blake?
I know Mr Blake.
Are you going to this grande soiree,
Gillingham? I am.
Mm. You kept that under your hat.
Dear me. We seem to be
the only people not invited.
What do you think we've done wrong?
Er... You'd be very welcome,
if you wanted to come.
Won't Lady Grantham mind?
Do I spy a dog in the manger?
Not at all.
A dog in the manger tries to protect
a thing he has no use for,
whereas I am looking forward
to this evening very much indeed.
Play nicely, children.
Do you know how these things work?
There's a dinner first and then most
people arrive after half past nine.
Then I shall do what most people do.
Am I glad to see you! We've been
struggling a bit without Mrs Bute.
And will Mrs Levinson's arrival
make things simpler, do you think?
I... As a matter of fact,
I'd value your opinion.
Her Ladyship has asked me to organise
a treat for the staff after the ball
as a thank you.
Well, that's very kind.
They've started opening the new
Science Museum in South Kensington,
even though it's not finished,
and I can't decide between that
and a visit to the Crystal Palace
on its new site at Sydenham Hill.
I see. And this is a fun day
as a thank you, is it?
Yes. I think it's very generous.
So do I.
Very generous indeed.
Maybe you should try your ideas
on the staff,
see what they jump at.
Hmm.
Mother! I'm so sorry. I thought
you said you'd be here after five.
Well, we just got away early.
I didn't think I had to make
an appointment.
I had a last fitting and...
Hello, Harold. Hello.
How are you?
A long way from home is how I am.
Harold and I will be spending
some time seeing Europe -
Madrid, Rome, Paris -
and we will enjoy ourselves.
I hope so but somehow I doubt it.
And this is because you
want to put a little space between
you and the Teapot Dome business?
Oh, let's not bring that up again.
It should've have worked.
I'm not much in a drawing room
but I am good at business -
Harold, Harold, we... No.
We came 3,500 miles
so we could change the subject.
(BELL TOLLING)
Can I help you with that?
I was carrying too many.
You've been avoiding me.
No, I haven't, I've just been busy
these past few months.
Anyway, I'm here now.
I'll get on with this marking.
I'm going to the pub
to get something to eat.
Why don't you join me?
I assume Edith got off all right?
Yes, she did
and she took Mrs Hughes and Daisy
with her.
I'm just going to the Grantham Arms
to get some dinner. Oh.
May I present Miss Bunting?
She teaches at the school.
Does she?
I wanted to say goodbye.
I may not see you before I go.
Ah!
My niece is being presented
on Tuesday.
I'm joining them for the supper
afterwards at the Palace.
How nice.
And you're coming up later
for her ball, aren't you, Branson?
Mm. We're off! So sorry.
Well, I'll say my goodbyes.
Does the offer of dinner
still stand?
Hmm.
Right, the first course is ready
to go up.
The souffle mix is done
for the savoury
and I'll make a bechamel
for the cauliflower.
Thank God for you, Daisy. I've never
known your true value till now.
You seem to be in charge,
not like an assistant at all.
We've worked together a long time.
Ever thought of going it alone?
Do you always try
and change people's lives after
you've known them half an hour?
Mr Levinson, might I ask if you'd be
willing to play the footman
on occasion while you're here?
What? Not every day but when
we have a big evening, like tonight
or Lady Rose's ball.
It's normal in England for the valets
to help out in this way
but it may not be in America.
We don't entertain much but OK.
You're very kind.
I brought some spare liveries
with me,
if you ask James or Molesley
to show you.
I will. And, Mr Carson, my employer
is called Levinson, not me.
In this house, you both are.
She was not seeing you off.
Sounded like it.
Have you found her very hard?
Losing Sybil was hard.
Compared to that,
everything else has been easy.
Will you show me the house? What?
Oh. Aren't you allowed
to bring your friends back?
It's not a question
of being allowed.
Then what is it a question of?
Yes, quite.
I wish Tom had arrived.
It's so nice to hear you say that.
No, I mean, he's bringing Isis
and I do miss her.
Do you know Lady Grantham's mother,
Mrs Levinson, and her son?
This is Lord Aysgarth.
A pleasure.
It's quite a crowd.
Yes, but plenty of old friends.
Excuse me.
That's Lord Harrowby. They haven't
seen each other for ages.
He clearly thinks that Lord Harrowby
is more alluring than we are.
The Lady Rosamund Painswick
and Mr Terence Sampson.
What the devil...? I looked in
at the Warwicks on my way here.
And Mr Sampson was saying that he'd
stayed at Downton not long ago,
so I made him come with me.
She wouldn't take no for an answer.
We're happy to see you here,
Mr Sampson. Thank you.
Do you know Lord Aysgarth?
I do. Sampson and I are old friends.
How are you, Billy?
Did you really keep it a secret from
Charles you were coming tonight?
I didn't keep it a secret,
I just didn't tell him.
You certainly don't give up easily.
Well, I won't give up at all.
You're in for a dry night.
No bad thing around this family.
I had a nasty brush with them
up in Yorkshire last year.
Who are they? Lady Grantham's mother
and brother,
over from America, I suppose.
Interesting.
It would be if he plays cards. Why?
They're absolutely made of money.
How do you think the Downton roof
still keeps out the rain?
Do you hear that, Madeleine?
Would you care for one of these?
I think they're quite nice.
Have you lost your mind?
Why? What have I done?
You're a footman,
not a travelling salesman.
Please keep your opinions
on the catering to yourself.
(SIGHS)
How's it going?
Her Ladyship seems pleased.
We're taking up the buffet now.
I only hope we've got enough.
Dinner, supper and no doubt
a big breakfast tomorrow?
It's a wonder they're not all
the size of a tub.
Oh, Anna, there's an appeal
at the Scottish church
in Pont Street for old clothes.
They're collecting
for Russian refugees.
You won't have brought anything with
you that you'd want to throw away
but you might spread the word.
Of course.
I've been on at Mr Bates to take
advantage of being in London
and get a few things.
Trouble is, he does hate shopping.
That must be because he's a man.
Do you know England well,
Mr Levinson? Er, not really.
He hasn't been here
since my daughter got married.
But don't worry. I'm well prepared
for cold baths, warm drinks
and, most of all, the food.
As I said, he doesn't travel much.
They're going into supper.
Harold, why don't you take
Miss Allsopp into the dining room?
Well...
You needn't if you don't want to.
Are you determined to put me off?
OK! Well, if that's what you want.
So shall we? I don't see why not.
Why not what?
Some of us are going on
to the Embassy later.
Oh, what fun.
Oh, well, you can come,
if you'd like. I will.
Why is Sampson here?
Aunt Rosamund brought him.
Papa's livid but there's nothing
to be done. He can't make a scene.
I sometimes feel
we should make more scenes
about things
that really matter to us.
Wouldn't be very English.
No, but I envy it.
All those Latins screaming
and shouting
and hurling themselves
into graves.
I bet they feel much better
afterwards.
I wonder. I think
once you've let it out
it must be hard to get it back in.
Let's go through.
But when do you use this?
This is our sitting room, really.
The drawing room is more formal.
This is for tea or writing letters
or anything like that.
(CHUCKLES) I'd feel as if
I were having tea
in the Victoria and Albert Museum.
No, it's nice, when everyone's here
and the fire's going.
And I'll bet you say
you haven't changed.
So you've seen everything.
Well, the main rooms.
Let me just look down
from the gallery,
then you can take me home.
I'm sorry. I feel a bit awkward,
to be honest,
with them all being away.
Well, I...
I asked if it was allowed.
It's not that, really.
Are they all for the Crawleys?
These are the marriages.
One side's Crawley and the other is
the arms for every Countess.
And the present Lady Grantham?
I don't see one with a dollar sign.
Can I help, sir?
Er, no.
We were just going down.
That is, we only just came up.
And now we're going down again.
Whatever you say, sir.
I'm taking Miss Bunting home. Please
don't lock up till I get back.
Very good, sir.
You did well. Everyone was saying
how delicious the kedgeree was.
Well, that were Daisy's work.
Mr Levinson had three helpings
and he thought he wouldn't
care for English food.
You've converted him, Daisy,
and that's something to be proud of.
What's so funny?
Freda was showing us a letter.
What's so special about a letter?
Because of who wrote it.
Rose, you must be tiddly.
Oh, I think I am a bit.
It's my fault.
I never should have mentioned it.
Isn't anyone going to dance?
Mr Levinson,
Madeleine's dying to dance.
Will you rescue her?
Oh, I watch dancing, I don't do it.
I don't believe that. Off you go!
And what about you, Freda? If you
promise not to step on my toes.
I'm afraid Father forced me on you.
Oh, don't worry. I'm used to it.
Used to what? Fathers wanting me
to dance with their daughters.
Would you care to dance? Oh, there's
Nell Foster! How topping.
Can you look after our bags?
Of course.
There's no need for you to stay.
I like to keep an eye on things,
sir.
Do it Mr Carson's way.
Only last night...
I was concerned
you may have misunderstood.
Sir?
I was having dinner
with Miss Bunting in the village
and she was curious
to look around the house...
..Mr Barrow.
She might perhaps see it to
more advantage in the daylight, sir.
Yes. And I'm sure she'll be back.
The point is we only went upstairs
so she could enjoy the view
down into the hall.
I wouldn't want you to think
any different.
However you wish to command me,
I am your servant, Mr Branson,
but I was not aware I was under
orders as to what I might think.
I thought I might arrive and find
you'd already left for London.
As a matter of fact, I'm going up
this morning with Lady Grantham.
I wanted to say you were kind
to write. That's all, really.
Well, when I decided to go
to Rose's ball,
I felt it was wrong not to tell you,
since you'd asked.
What changed your mind?
I suppose it came to me
that these balls and presentations
and comings out
are not just aristocratic folderol
but traditions
by which members of this family
measure their progress through life.
And you wanted to be part of that?
Well, I felt by dismissing it
as trivia,
I was being smug and intolerant.
Do they know what they have in you?
I know what I have in them.
So, have you decided whether or not
you will come to the ball?
Oh, how can you ask?
Of course I will!
But I don't understand.
How can you suddenly be an editor?
I won't be, not in that way,
but Michael gave me
power of attorney.
It didn't matter before
but now they need some decisions.
And you'll have to make them
until he...?
Well, until either he comes back
or...
Is there a will, do you know?
It might be useful.
To help you find out what he wanted.
Wants. I'm sure there is but...
I don't know what's in it yet.
I'll find out.
But what about his child?
Doesn't she have some rights?
His child is not his child any more
or yours.
She belongs
to nice Mr and Mrs Schroder
and lives in Geneva
with the rest of her family.
It's all very well saying that
but it doesn't change anything.
Only because you won't let it.
There was no formal agreement.
Maybe not
but it wouldn't be fair to the
Schroders to go back on your word.
Dear Aunt Rosamund, I'm so grateful
for all you've done
and I'm not pulling rank but the fact
remains, you've never been a mother.
You'll never guess.
Oh, try. What is it?
Alfred's finished his course
and they've taken him on.
What, permanent at the Ritz?
As an under chef.
But that won't be for long.
He's going to be famous.
Whoo-hoo! Who is?
Alfred Nugent.
He was a footman at Downton
but he's working at the Ritz now.
He's on his way.
That seems quite
the American dream to me -
poor boy from the sticks
becomes famous hotelier.
Well, I don't know if it's American
or not but I think it's smashing.
..was still here. Nonsense.
What's he doing?
Oh, he just came to see me off.
Huh! But we mustn't lose any time
or we'll miss our train.
I know I'm late.
It couldn't be helped.
Cora insisted I come without a maid.
I can't believe she understood
the implications. Which are?
How do I get a guard
to take my luggage?
And when we arrive in London,
what happens then?
Fear not.
I've never travelled WITH a maid.
You can share my knowledge
of the jungle.
Can't you even offer help
without sounding like a trumpeter on
the peak of the moral high ground?
And must you always sound like
the sister of Marie-Antoinette?
The Queen of Naples was
a stalwart figure.
I take it as a compliment.
You take everything as a compliment.
I advise you to do the same.
It saves many an awkward moment.
Goodbye.
Success. I have finally persuaded
Mr Bates to buy a new overcoat,
so the refugees can have this.
That's just what they need.
Are you sure? Take it. He'd only go
on wearing it if it's in the house.
Well, they'll be very grateful.
I'd better get back.
There's always plenty of fuss
before a presentation.
There is but I think it's exciting.
Seems odd to me that a courtesy
and a nod from the throne
can turn you from a girl into a woman
but who are we to argue?
Oh!
May I help, Mrs Hughes?
I was just looking for Anna
but it doesn't matter.
(CHEERING)
Now we have to go our separate ways.
I feel quite nervous. Nonsense.
Onwards to the breach.
The Countess of Grantham presenting
the Lady Rose MacClare.
Thank you, Lady Grantham.
I hope you don't want
to powder your nose. Why not?
Because all that's on offer is
a chamber pot behind that screen.
The glamour of court life!
Who's presenting you?
My father's eldest sister.
Aunt Violet wanted to present me
but we got round it.
She'll be at the supper
as a consolation.
Papa's coming.
So are my mother and my brother.
Mr Levinson's here and Mrs Levinson?
How did you manage that?
Lord Grantham is
our Lord Lieutenant.
And he pulled a string to get them
in? Father will be so pleased.
Madeleine. Gosh, that's me.
Good luck.
So she's in the library
and she's on her own. Are you sure?
What do you want with her?
Nothing that would interest you.
Mr Carson, I wonder...
I'm sorry. Don't mind me.
I'm just leaving.
Can I help?
I wanted to ask you, man to man,
if anything's going on between Daisy
and the fella working at the Ritz.
Going on? Nothing goes on in
any house where I am in authority.
Of course not. I didn't mean that.
What did you mean?
I think you know.
The "fella" is called Alfred.
There is no romance
between him and Daisy.
He has left our employ.
I doubt they'll meet in the future.
Because I wouldn't like to push in
where I'm not wanted.
The Duchess of Margam presenting
the Lady Elizabeth Bailey George.
The Countess of Grantham presenting
the Lady Rose MacClare.
Lady Rose is Lord Flintshire's
daughter, sir.
Ah! The Prince of Wales has spoken
about your father's hospitality
in Bombay.
He was honoured to entertain
His Royal Highness, Your Majesty.
The Indian tour was a great success,
thanks to Lord Flintshire.
The Prince did splendidly, sir.
He was so popular wherever he went.
Yes. The Prince is never short
of popularity.
Lady Grantham.
The Countess of Derwentwater
presenting the Lady Jane Radcliffe.
So Bates was in London that day.
You say it as if you already knew.
Does Anna suspect anything?
Absolutely not. She knows nothing.
So will you tell her now, My Lady?
I gather you won't.
No. No, I'm handing this to you.
Meaning leave it alone?
We can't know what happened
on that street.
Maybe he was in London
for an innocent reason
and nowhere near Piccadilly.
But this I will say. If he was there
to avenge his wife's honour,
I won't condemn him for it.
I'm sorry but I won't.
Oh! All done?
Presented, photographed, done.
You both looked splendid.
You didn't look so bad yourself.
The unfair advantage
of a court position.
I hear the King was very talkative,
for him.
How was the Queen?
You know - she sort of sits there
being Queen Mary-like.
Any chance of meeting them later?
Hardly.
His Majesty is not an admirer
of the New World.
You might do better
with the Prince of Wales.
I'm not one of those Englishmen
who hates New York
but a great city can be
a lonely place.
Can't everywhere? But you'd only
be lonely if you wanted to be.
Do you know Newport?
Why?
I stayed there before the war with
the Duchess of Marlborough's mother.
I thought it was wonderful.
As a matter of fact,
I'm in Newport quite a lot.
I have what they call a cottage
on Bellevue Avenue.
Really? I didn't know.
Didn't you? Huh!
I feel rather guilty
about leaving Isobel behind. Why?
She brought a book with her.
That should keep her occupied.
What sort of book?
I can only tell you
that on the train
it was far more interesting than me.
Your father's paying
a lot of attention to my mother.
You think we ought to tell him
she only has an income for life?
You are funny!
Oh, that's right.
The English upper classes never talk
about money. We don't like to.
But you don't mind thinking
about it.
Er... Or at least,
your father doesn't.
We should tell him
before he's in too deep.
When she dies, all the capital
reverts to me. He ought to know.
Rose. Oh! Are you at all
the presentation courts?
You are good! There are only four
and David... I mean,
the Prince likes me here.
He said you were very sweet
about him.
Is something the matter?
Do you remember that letter we were
laughing about the other night? Yes.
Well, the thing is,
when I got home, it was missing.
It wasn't in my bag
and I know I put it back. I saw you.
I was so hoping
you might have taken it, as a prank.
I won't be a bit cross if you did.
I'm afraid not. Try Madeleine.
It wasn't her. It... It's just...
If it falls into the wrong hands...
No need to explain.
Has anyone been in touch,
asking for money?
I wish they had.
Then I'd know how to get it back.
Ah! Do they talk much,
the King and Queen?
They were very kind. Well, you're
not presented for conversation.
This is Mrs Dudley Ward.
Of course you are!
Have we met? No. I read about you
in the American newspapers.
Gossip, really.
Nothing to worry about.
But never give them a real story.
How do you do? Harold Levinson.
You're mistaken, sir. I'm not Harold
Levinson, whoever he may be.
Er, no, no, no. I'm Harold Levinson.
Then why did you say I was?
Cousin Robert? Mm?
I've got such a funny question.
It seems an awful thing to say
but do you think your friend
Mr Sampson might be capable
of something dishonourable?
He's not my friend.
Why do you ask? Well...
It was when we were at the Palace,
at the supper.
Go on.
Do you remember Mrs Dudley Ward?
Did you notice how upset she was?
He wanted Miss Allsopp to go
on a picnic luncheon in the park?
The picnic was my idea.
He thinks he's offended her
and he wants to make it up.
He can't go on a picnic
with a young lady on her own.
What is he thinking of? Why not?
Because we're not in America
and she isn't a chorus girl.
Don't worry! He's asked her father
and Mrs Levinson to come along.
And who's going to prepare
this picnic, when it's at home?
Daisy can make it!
And come along, to help me serve.
Don't be daft. I work
in the kitchen, I don't serve.
Then I'll serve! You get it ready
and set it out and...
I'll serve.
Oh, I see.
You see what? It's not set in stone
that you shouldn't help at a picnic.
I can spare you,
if you think they'll come.
Lord Aysgarth will come if he knows
old mother Levinson's aboard.
Oh, very respectful, I must say!
I'll be sorry if he means to revive
the ways of his grandpapa,
winking at every beauty
in an opera box.
It must be a lonely job.
All the public want is
a happy marriage at the Palace.
Is it so much to ask?
And anyway, why did Mrs Dudley Ward
have the letter in her handbag?
I expect it was a love thing.
It won't be much of a love thing
when it's in the American papers.
Do you think that's why he took it?
Sampson took it to make money.
The question is whether he means
to blackmail Mrs Dudley Ward
or sell it to the foreign press.
No wonder she was in such a state.
I can't tell you what it said.
Don't! I'm a monarchist
and that's why I would like
the letter retrieved
and why I do not wish to know
its contents.
I feel so guilty!
If I hadn't joked about it,
he would never have suspected
it was in her handbag.
Good God.
Then we have to do something,
at once.
If we're lucky, the letter will be
at Sampson's flat.
We must get him away from there
and someone must go in and -
Steal it? You can't steal something
that's already been stolen.
But how would we get in?
We can't very well pick the lock.
James, could you please ask Bates
to come to the drawing room?
Are we ready? We are, sir.
Only, Ivy has a basket
of kitchen things to carry
and it will be a bit of a squash
for her and me and the basket
in the front.
You mean, you want to sit next to me
in the back?
And if I were His Lordship,
would you ask to sit next to him?
Well, I doubt we'd be in
the same car, sir.
If you were?
We could just tie my basket
on the back.
I think that would be
the best solution.
Good. That's settled, then.
You've made everything I asked for?
It wasn't very complicated.
Mr Levinson does not like
complicated food.
That's why he likes English cooking.
How are you going to manage it,
now old Lady Grantham's going
and Mrs Crawley?
It's a lot of work.
You'd better take James with you.
We can manage with Mr Molesley
for lunch. Yes.
Would you mind? I'm a footman.
I don't have the right to mind.
Thank you, Wat Tyler.
Where are you meeting them?
A place called the Albert Memorial,
but er...will I know it
when I see it?
You most certainly will,
I can promise you that.
Now, I've got rugs, cushions
and folding chairs.
Come on. You'd better get started.
It's very good of you to spare her.
It won't kill me.
She deserves a bit of luck.
I'm afraid that boy's interest
in her may not be entirely proper.
Mr Carson, all women need
someone to show a bit of interest
every now and then,
preferably in a manner
that's not entirely proper.
Hm, hm.
Bates, during your time...away,
did you ever meet a man
who could copy someone's writing?
Do you mean a forger, My Lord?
Yes, I suppose I do.
What would he be required to do?
We have to gain entry
to someone's flat,
so the porter needs to be told
to unlock the door.
The order will come in the form
of a signed note. I see.
I assume we have a sample
of this person's writing.
Do we?
He sent a bread and butter letter
after our party the other night.
Then I can get it done.
How long will it take?
If I can have the letter
straightaway,
I believe I can supply the note
by the end of the afternoon.
So the man is here in London? He is,
My Lord. What a stroke of luck.
I know this sounds rather dodgy,
Bates,
but there is nothing underhand
in what we're trying to achieve -
quite the reverse.
Your word is enough for me, My Lord.
Please don't ruin everything,
not when it's over and done
and nobody knows.
Granny knows. Is she going to reveal
the bastard child
of her own granddaughter?
Remember, you were never going to
mention it, even if he came back.
I know I said that but I don't think
I could keep to it now.
Why? Is there some news?
Not really. A bit.
It seems he got into a fight
with a gang of toughs
the first night he was in Munich.
A gang of toughs?
They're quite well-known, apparently.
They wear brown shirts and go around
preaching the most horrible things.
Anyway, a man who was there says
that Michael took exception
to what they were saying.
He should have had the sense
to keep out of it.
But surely, if they know these men,
they can question them
and find out what happened.
You'd think so.
Oh, my dear. I can be normal
most of the time for weeks on end
but then I think I might never see
him again and...
I know. But that's not the point.
If Michael is dead, if I do inherit,
then I have to give at least half
to the baby.
Don't you see? No, I don't.
But if you really must,
do it anonymously.
It wouldn't be hard.
This is for the best.
If you'll only keep silent,
there'll be other loves,
other children.
Don't cheat yourself of that,
I beg you.
I don't know.
Then trust me...because I do.
What's that you're doing?
Something for His Lordship. Hm.
Are you enjoying being in London?
I am.
Makes a nice change.
Oh, it does for me, right enough.
I haven't been here since I buried
my mother, halfway through the war.
Has it been that long?
My, my.
Of course I understand
why the letter must be recovered.
I don't see why
it has to involve me.
Someone has to fetch the letter
whilst we distract Sampson.
Can't Rose go?
On her own? Have a heart.
Well, you, then. I'm the one
hosting the card game.
The question is, who else can play?
They must be genuine
or it will smell fishy.
Tony Gillingham would come
but we'd have to tell him.
I know who'd play and bring Sampson
and we needn't say a word.
Lord Aysgarth.
Grandmama can sit on his lap.
I don't want her here. She'll make
some crack and give the game away.
What can we do with her?
Send a note to Rosamund.
Ask her to take Martha to a play.
And Mama and Isobel.
Tell her to give them supper
afterwards.
They'll have to change
once they're back from their picnic,
so we won't be stuck with them long.
I hate to lie.
I'll do it. I don't mind lying.
We ought to give the men dinner.
It will make it more normal.
But won't Sampson be suspicious?
He must be aware you don't like him.
I'll tell Aysgarth
that Harold will play.
Fleecing your uncle will be
too tempting for Sampson to resist.
Suppose Uncle Harold would rather go
to the theatre?
Ask Lord Aysgarth
to bring his daughter.
I don't like the idea of you two
setting off to burgle his flat.
I can't allow it. We could ask
Evelyn Napier. He's in France.
Mr Blake, then. But I know
what the letter looks like.
Suppose the porter calls the police?
Do you want the heir to the throne
to be lampooned across the world
with a story that will never sleep,
even when he's safely crowned
and married to a princess?
No, but I do feel he's brought it
down on his own head.
Even if that's true, we introduced
Sampson to Mrs Dudley Ward
and Rose as good as gave him
the letter.
This family is responsible
for the whole ghastly debacle.
(DOOR SLAMS)
The pate was delicious,
now the fish mousse is delicious
and all my life I've been warned off
English food.
I'm glad we score in one category.
The menu was very unoriginal.
I like my food good.
I don't want it original.
So England is the right place
for you.
So, I know you're a lord
but what kind of lord are you?
There are different kinds?
The British peerage is
a fountain of variety.
It's just a lowly barony,
I'm afraid,
but it's quite old.
So you are not Lady Madeleine?
No, but she's an Honourable.
Who would doubt it?
So how long is it
before you go home?
Late Friday we leave for Paris
and then for Rome.
I envy you, to see Europe
as you will see it.
What do you mean? Drifting
from great hotel to great hotel,
no-one to hurry you,
no-one to pester you -
like the world as it used to be.
You mean, with no expense spared.
I meant how charming it would be
to see it with Mrs Levinson.
Another whisky, would you?
Is it going all right?
As far as you're concerned.
But the old lady treats His Lordship
like a bad smell.
Rose says you have
quite a reputation at home.
As a playboy, you mean?
I know it's hard to believe
but it's true.
I... I own a yacht
and I like pretty girls...
..and er...
Can I be honest? Please.
The best thing is those girls don't
expect a thing from me
beyond a good time and a diamond
bracelet as a thank-you note.
And do you like that too?
Nobody gets disappointed.
And I hate to disappoint people.
Is it why you never married?
Oh, what a leading question.
I thought well-born English girls
were supposed to be reticent
and refined.
That was before the war. Ah!
Well, I would find it hard
to respect any woman
who wished to marry me.
But plenty of nice women would want
to marry you, Mr Levinson.
You mean, because I'm rich?
You are strange. You invite me here
today as an apology
and yet you seem bent
on offending me again. I hope not.
Because I like you very much,
Miss Allsopp.
More than any lady
I have ever known,
if I may use the term.
But you won't go along
with Papa's scheme? No.
And you wouldn't want me to.
How do you know that?
Because you're better
than your father, Miss Allsopp.
Will you warn your mother off him?
Oh, my mother can look after
herself, believe me.
Can you really manage? Oh, yes.
You were going to be ten anyway,
now everyone's here,
so 14 makes no difference.
I only hope Mrs Hughes can sort out
the sleeping arrangements.
Mm. We're packed in like sardines
but I suppose it's not for long.
Ooh! If the family's sardines,
My Lady, the staff are like maggots.
Erm, where's Bates? He were in
the servants' hall earlier on.
Thank you, Mrs Patmore.
My Lady.
His Lordship asked if there's
any news on the note for tonight.
It's here, My Lady.
But that's extraordinary. How did
you get him to do it so quickly?
He had nothing else on. It's all
quite proper, whatever it may seem.
As His Lordship assured me.
Good luck with the recovery plan
when you get to Mr Sampson's flat.
We'll let you know.
Well, I'd better tell His Lordship
we're all set.
It's a funny thing about London,
isn't it,
the way it seems to draw one
into peculiar situations?
Like any big city.
I expect many people must regret
things they got up to in London.
Is there anything I can do, My Lady?
It's only that we've forced
this dinner on Mrs Patmore
without warning.
I was checking to see
if she was on top of it.
Mrs Patmore is very resilient.
I'm not sure I can leave it alone,
with the ticket.
We're talking about a man's life,
Mrs Hughes.
Whatever we may think,
do we have a right to do nothing?
So Mr Bates must be ruined,
or even hanged,
because a vile, vicious monster is
no longer with us?
I'm sorry. What you're asking me
to do is wrong.
Whoever the man,
whatever the motive, it's wrong.
What? A card game? Here?
And what
are the ladies supposed to do?
Put feathers in their hair
and light the gentlemen's cigars?
You know, Rosamund wants to take you
to the theatre. Oh, I don't think so.
Oh, no. I'm too tired for an evening
of second-hand emotion.
Oh, me too. One outing's enough.
I'd rather stay in and play cards.
Oh, poker's not your game.
I hope you don't mind playing on
your first night here. Not at all.
Then we'll sit and talk
and leave the men to it.
So it doesn't strike you as odd?
No, not really. Well, not very.
And Mary's men, why are they coming?
Don't call them Mary's men.
They're coming for cards, Mama,
except for Charles Blake.
He doesn't play.
That is, he won't play tonight.
We could play a different game.
Oh, no, he has to go out.
He's taking Mary and me to see
a show. Not a very long show.
I wish you'd say what's going on.
Well, now, Isis, old girl.
Are you happy to be in London?
She's happy to see you.
I was no substitute.
Whoa! Well, the gang's all here,
I see.
Is that American for hello?
Harold, I don't believe
you've met Tom, Sybil's husband.
It seems strange we never met
when she was here to introduce us.
Well, I'm glad to know you now.
How curious these phrases are!
Could we get some tea?
With milk?
Well, I hope you enjoyed our picnic.
Of course we did.
Even if the combination of open-air
picnics and after-dinner poker
make me feel as though I've fallen
through a looking-glass
into the Dejeuner Sur L'Herbe.
It's lucky you don't exaggerate,
Mama.
Poker after dinner?
There's a message from Rosamund
that she's taking us to the theatre.
Not us - you. Why have I been
selected for this honour?
She was complaining
she doesn't see enough of you.
Enough for what?
Well, if I'm going to the theatre,
then I ought to change.
Yes. I should.
Have you heard from Alfred again?
Why would we?
Don't suppose he can be bothered
with us now, cooking for film stars
and the crowned heads of Europe.
I'll crown you if you don't get that
back on the heat.
No, but he's escaped, hasn't he?
Escaped from what?
Well, you know - ordinary life.
Oh!
Before you go in, My Lord.
What is it?
I wasn't sure whether to tell you
but I was put in charge of Downton
when you left.
Is something wrong? Not in that way.
And you may think
it's not my business
but when the family's honour is
concerned, My Lord,
it is my business.
Go on. The other night
I was patrolling the galleries,
making sure everything was
ship-shape before I turned in,
when I ran into Mr Branson
with a lady.
Upstairs? Just as I said, My Lord.
On the bedroom gallery.
What time was this? Oh, quite late.
I can't say which room
they'd been in or if they'd been
in a room at all except...
I don't know why else
they'd be up there.
Anyway, they went downstairs and
he drove her back to the village.
Who was this lady?
He said her name was Miss Bunting,
a Miss Sarah Bunting.
Of course, Mr Branson is still
a young man
and he can't be expected to stay
single all his life but even so...
Thank you, Barrow.
Yes, My Lord.
Do we have anything I can take up
some ice in? Why do you need ice?
Mr Levinson seems to want it
in everything he drinks.
Er, I'm glad you're all here.
I have something
I want to tell you.
Her Ladyship wants to give us all
a day out while we're in the south.
Oh!
I've been thinking
a visit to the Science Museum.
Or perhaps to see where they've put
the Crystal Palace!
Then there's the Royal Institution.
Or the Natural History Museum.
Of course, Westminster Abbey is
always a good day out.
Well, I'm sure we'll come up
with something.
Erm... Could I have that ice?
Mrs Hughes, did you get rid
of that old coat?
I did. They were very grateful.
We should tell that to Mr Bates.
I took it without saying and
he hadn't gone through the pockets.
There was nothing in them,
was there?
Nothing that matters now.
Well, that's a funny answer.
Can I help you, Miss Baxter?
No, no.
I hope Daisy gave you my message.
She did, yes.
So what's going on?
I know you. There's something.
Are you free, Miss Baxter? I've a
book I've been meaning to show you.
Thank you, Mr Molesley.
What was it you wanted to say?
You must promise
not to answer straightaway.
Not to answer what? Mr Levinson
wants you to come to America
to cook for him.
We'll be touring Europe for a month.
You have plenty of time to decide.
Then, if you agree,
he'll send you the fare
and I'll meet you in New York.
Are you serious? He says he'll be
teased for hiring an English cook
but he loves your food - he does.
That's not what I were expecting.
Terribly out of practice.
Haven't played since Downton.
It's rather sad poor Mr Gregson
won't be joining us.
You've heard about that?
Everyone has.
It's quite a mystery
but I confess to a certain relief
he won't be at the table tonight.
Did he give you a difficult time
of it?
To be honest, I wasn't sure he was
playing strictly according to Hoyle
but we'll leave it,
since the poor chap's missing.
I hope we can trust everyone
at the table tonight.
I'm disappointed. I was rather hoping
to find Mrs Levinson here.
I'm sure you were.
I gather you've been entertaining
in our absence.
Have I? Barrow mentioned a friend of
yours came up for dinner one night.
Not for dinner but I brought her
to the house after dinner.
After dinner?
She...wanted to have a look.
We ought to concentrate or Sampson
will have his way with us.
(CHUCKLING)
This is so kind of you.
Sorry to hear that Mr Sampson was
taken ill, miss.
I'm sure it isn't serious but
we do need to gather some things.
Let me know when you're done and
I'll come and lock up. Thank you!
It's rather sad to see the truth
behind Mr Sampson's smooth facade.
Cheating at cards can't be
very lucrative after all.
Never mind that.
Charles, you take the desk,
and, Mary, we'll search the bedroom.
They say men hide things
in their sock drawer.
Why's that, do you think?
It's a deterrent.
What could be more revolting
than rummaging through
a strange man's socks? Ugh!
You're very thoughtful, Miss Baxter.
Am I?
It's no use ganging up
with Mr Molesley.
He can't protect you like I can.
And he doesn't know what I know,
does he?
He knows how to be kind, Mr Barrow.
He has the advantage of you there.
Erm, mine, I believe. Sorry!
Oh, so you do have the cards!
I must play more!
AYSGARTH: You said Sampson would
have the trick of it.
I haven't had a hand all night.
Gentlemen, have we had enough?
Surely not.
We've only just begun.
TONY: No. No, I think that's it.
I gather we've failed to protect
the Prince from his recklessness?
(SIGHS) So now the press
will go to town. I'm afraid so.
But I daresay his lack of judgment
would have tripped him up
sooner or later.
Rather gloomy for a monarchist.
I'm a realist monarchist.
I think someone's waiting for you.
I should be off.
I'm so grateful - really.
Well, if it does all blow up, I hope
he finds out how hard we tried.
I can't be sad, though. No?
You were in trouble
and you called on me.
It seems a very positive step,
which I'd like to see repeated
immediately, if possible.
Must I be in trouble again so soon?
I mean it, Mary.
Give me a chance.
Are you sure? My lot's going down
and your lot's coming up.
Is that a receipt
for a peaceful coexistence?
I wouldn't put it like that.
I'd say I believe in the future.
And so could you.
I'd better go.
I'll see you at the ball.
Mr Bates, Lady Rose is back
and she asked me to tell you
that the note worked
but they couldn't find
what they were looking for,
whatever that means.
What does it mean?
James, when they leave
I'll need a hand with the coats.
I'd like to help, Mr Carson.
Oh, that would be appreciated.
Thank you.
So, from tomorrow,
it's full speed ahead for the ball.
Could we tell them about the outing,
to keep their spirits up?
Have you had any further thoughts?
Well, I was wondering if we might
go for something more obvious.
Madame Tussaud's, perhaps.
There are interesting
historical figures to be seen there
and not just sensational ones.
Are there?
Are you all right, my darling?
I never know what's going on
inside that head of yours,
not these days.
But you do know I would never do
anything to hurt you, don't you?
What an extraordinary thing to say!
Extraordinary or not, it's true.
Whatever I may do,
it would never be to hurt you.
Good night, Papa.
Do you mean we've all been kept
in the dark for nothing?
I'm afraid so.
Kept in the dark about what?
Oh, just, some romantic scheme.
Nothing more.
Might it concern
my old friend Aysgarth,
who came here to see
a certain lady from across the seas?
A certain lady destined to go back
across the seas with any luck.
Lady Grantham, I'm very touched
by your generosity to me.
I know we English don't speak
of such things
but I won't forget it.
That's quite all right.
Good night.
It was nice of you to come tonight,
after our conversation earlier.
I hope you'll be at the ball.
Why wouldn't I be?
Good.
I expect you'll have another game
tomorrow. How well you know me.
Thank you. Which is Mr Sampson's?
I have it here. Thank you, Mr
Carson.
Don't you ever get tired of it?
It's a lucrative game.
Thanks. Did you talk to Mr Levinson?
There we are, sir.
And there's no chance
of Mrs Levinson...? Good night.
I'm worn out, I'm worn out.
I feel as if I've spent
the whole evening trapped
in the cast of a whodunit.
Nobody's done it,
that's the problem.
Good night, Mama. Good night, dear.
I beg your pardon, My Lord.
What's this?
It occurred to me, My Lord,
that were I in possession
of a very sensitive document,
I would not leave it unguarded
in my home
but rather, I would take it with me
wherever I went.
So I helped a gentleman
on with his coat.
He left it in his overcoat?
It was in his inside breast pocket
and now it is safely in your hands.
I'll see you upstairs, My Lord.
(GASPS)
I don't believe it! How?
Mr Sampson appears to have
dropped it and Bates picked it up.
He dropped it? Aren't we fortunate?
Fortunate is one word for it.
So it was a happy ending, My Lady?
A happy ending for the Prince.
A crisis for the monarchy has been
averted,
although given his character,
I wonder if we won't see another
before he's finished.
But the next one won't be the fault
of the Crawley family.
But seriously,
we are so much in Bates' debt.
I'll thank him in the morning
but would you tell him
how grateful we are?
He'll be glad to have been of use,
My Lady.
He's very loyal to the family
but you already know that.
I do and the family is loyal to him.
To both of you.
Huh!
(BUZZ OF CONVERSATION)
We should start the dancing
and I think it would be nice
if you began it with Rose.
Family duty comes in many forms.
Wait a minute. What's this?
(GASPING AND WHISPERING)
Lady Grantham,
I know we're just crashers
and we haven't been invited -
well, I haven't, anyway -
but we hoped you wouldn't mind.
You honour this house
with your presence, sir.
I don't know if the dancing has
started yet
but perhaps His Royal Highness
and Rose could...?
Would you permit me
to open the ball?
♪ WALDTEUFEL: The Skaters' Waltz
If she isn't a darling of London
society after a kick-off like this,
it won't be his fault.
Are you glad you came?
I mean, these are your people now.
You must remember that.
This is your family.
This may be my family
but these are not quite my people.
That sounds like a challenge.
Does it?
Well, here's another.
Would you like to dance?
Oh! Well...are you sure?
Well, then, I accept the challenge.
I know... I know I can trust you
to steer.
How did you manage this?
I told him in his whole life
he'd never owed more to anyone
than he does to Rose.
And did you tell him why?
Certainly not.
But he trusts me
and he's a faithful little chap.
So am I, Freda.
Annoyingly, so am I.
What do you mean, no?
What do you think I mean?
It's not a very complicated word.
Don't you want to be Lady Aysgarth
and rank alongside your daughter?
Lord Aysgarth, I'm modern.
I don't hanker for those days
before the war.
And I don't really want to spend
the rest of my life
among people who think me loud
and opinionated and common.
But I assure you, they wouldn't.
Ah, yes, they would.
And, you know, they'd be right
because I think
THEY are narrow and pompous
and boring.
Well, then, why did you encourage me?
Because I thought that it would add
to the fun of the trip.
And I was right.
So, why don't you come
and visit Newport
and I will rustle up...
old rich widows
who want titles much more than I do?
Wouldn't that call it quits?
This is not me. London has remade me
in a different image.
Maybe London has released you
to be seen as you really are.
Ah, Miss Allsopp - Madeleine.
And please don't think too harshly
of us.
Father is frightened.
You see, he doesn't know how to live
without money. Ah!
Well, thank you for your honesty.
I'm only sorry I couldn't help.
You have helped.
I won't play his game again
and you're the one
I have to thank for that. Hmm.
But now I'm going to help you.
I'm flattered you should want to.
There you go again!
You say you're only fit
for good-time girls
who see a profit in friendship.
And you don't agree, huh?
I know that any woman,
no matter who she was,
would be lucky to claim you
as her husband.
You're kind, clever,
and much too modest.
And I speak without guile because
I know you have escaped my net.
Thank you.
When do you go?
We get the boat train Friday.
Hmm. But you'll pleased to hear
I'm going to hire an English cook.
My valet appears
to have recruited one.
Will you write?
Tell me how things are going?
Madeleine? I should be delighted...
..Harold.
Can we stop without my having
to hand you over to someone else?
Let's hide.
Are you enjoying yourself? It's
exciting to see the Prince of Wales.
We're going to watch from
the basement steps when he leaves.
I don't know
what Mr Barrow's got over you
and I don't want to know
but he mustn't make you do things
that aren't right
and you can't let him bully you.
That's easy to say.
I know.
But if he draws you
into his schemes, that's not going
to be easy for you either.
Sometimes, it's better to, you know,
take a risk
than to go down the wrong path -
that's all.
Are you taking this or should I
carry it up to the ballroom myself?
Sorry.
I gather it turned out well
the other night after all.
That's why the Prince came
to open the ball.
I'm glad.
Is there any progress on whether
it's going to turn out well for me?
Oh, Tony, I wish I knew.
I feel so cruel,
dangling you and Charles and
even Evelyn on the end of a string.
You didn't refuse Charles either?
I tried but he wouldn't have it.
Are you sure it's not him?
My destiny is to save Downton
for George
by spending every penny and every
waking minute holding it together.
Yes. Charles is on the other side
of that struggle.
He's an outsider who resents
the very people I come from.
Even if he loves me,
how can we pull as team?
Of course, I should sing and dance
to hear you say that
but you seem to have got
the wrong end of the stick
with Charles.
What do you mean? Charles is
the heir to his father's cousin,
Sir Severus Blake.
He is to inherit the baronetcy on
one of the largest estates in Ulster.
Charles?
But if that were true,
surely I would have heard of him?
Well, Sir Severus is
a distant relation
and Charles has always played it down
but he is not an outsider.
In fact, he's going to be
a lot more eligible than I am.
Why did no-one tell me this before?
Does it make a difference?
To know that he and I are
on the same side, yes,
of course it makes a difference.
You sound as though
the tide is running against me.
Tony...
A year ago,
I thought I'd be alone for ever.
That I would mourn Matthew
to the end of my days.
Now I know that isn't true, that
there will be a new life for me,
one day.
And even if I can't decide yet
what life that should be...
isn't it something
for us to celebrate?
It certainly is.
♪ STRAUSS: Vienna Blood Waltz
Oh, heavens. What is it?
Lord Merton, and he seems
to be headed in this direction.
Oh! No doubt to lead you down
the primrose path of dalliance.
Whoo!
Mrs Crawley, I hope you'll do me
the honour of dancing this waltz.
I'm really not much of a dancer.
Oh, nor I, so we're a perfect match.
Well...
Excuse me, please.
So did you enjoy it, after all?
I enjoyed it fine.
But we need to stand up to them,
you and I.
We may love them
but if we don't fight our corner,
they'll roll us out flat.
You're right.
Thank you for that.
I'm going home in the morning, Mama.
You don't mind, do you?
Of course not. Is there a reason?
Various reasons.
I might go to the Continent.
Not for long. Really?
Does it have anything
to do with Michael Gregson?
It has everything to do
with Michael Gregson.
Couldn't someone go for you?
I'm afraid not, Aunt Rosamund.
I'm absolutely afraid not.
Oh! Oh! Off to bed, are we?
Well, that's very sensible.
A woman your age needs her rest.
You need a rest cure if you are
taken in by that booby Aysgarth.
Violet, forgive me,
and I don't mean to be offensive,
but are you always this stuck-up?
Do tell me, do tell me -
is the new Lady Aysgarth all set
to hold London enthralled
with tales of how the West was won?
Well, actually, I turned him down.
Oh!
You surprise me.
Mm-hm. I'm sure.
You see, I have no wish
to be a great lady. No.
A decision that must be reinforced
whenever you look in the glass.
Violet, I don't mind
looking in the mirror
because what I see is a woman
who's not afraid of the future.
My world is coming nearer
and your world, it's slipping
further and further away.
Good night.
Hmm.
Breakfast is done but there are
still quite a few in the ballroom.
No, go to bed.
Take the others with you.
I'll keep James and give him
the rest of the morning off.
And what about you? It won't be the
first time I've gone without sleep.
We ought to have the outing settled
if we're going on Thursday.
Oh! I feel...
a little guilty about that.
I tried out my ideas on them and
I couldn't fire up any enthusiasm,
so I wonder if we should just settle
for a day by the sea.
I know it's a defeat
but what do you think?
We could take the Pullman
from Victoria.
A day-return ticket costs
12 shillings each.
It's a lot
but Her Ladyship's happy to pay.
Well, thank heaven you got there
in the end.
We've danced all night.
Your mother's gone to bed.
Do congratulate her
on such a triumph. I will.
Charles, why did you never tell me
about your cousin?
Or the estate in Ulster
or any of it?
I don't know, really.
At first, I wanted you not to assume
I shared your prejudices
because I came
from a similar background.
And later on? Later on?
Later on, I think I wanted to win you
by myself, alone.
Who told you? Evelyn? Well, I suppose
it could have been anyone.
Tony Gillingham told me.
Oh.
I thought it suited him for you
to think of me as an alien being.
I think he wants it to be
a fair fight.
Always assuming
we're the only two in the ring.
So now...
let battle commence?
Let battle commence.
Thank you. Just put it there.
So if you go tomorrow, how long
would you be in Switzerland?
Three or four days at the most.
So we've not got long to prepare.
I will pay you for the first month
this afternoon
but with three children,
you must have most
of the paraphernalia already.
You're right. We won't need much.
And you're quite sure your wife is
willing to take this on?
Marjie dotes on children, My Lady.
In fact, I'm not sure
we've had our last.
She'll love it like her own.
We'll need a decent story.
That the parents are dead
and the mother was a friend of yours
or something
and that's why you've taken her in.
Well, that's true, except of course
it's my friend and not yours.
But you don't want her here?
I can't have her here.
My parents disapproved
of my friendship with her mother.
They'd feel uncomfortable
for the baby to be in the house.
I see.
Which is why it has to be a secret.
I hope I can make you understand
how important that is.
I'll pay you whatever you want
but it has to be a complete secret
from my family.
I tell you what.
I think it should be our secret,
My Lady.
Ours and no-one else's.
I'll er...
send a letter to myself tonight
and tell Marjie it's about
an old friend of mine who's died
and asked for me to take the child.
She won't question it.
Then nobody but you and I will know.
Mr Drewe, would you do that for me?
For you and the little girl,
My Lady,
yes, I will.
How comforting it is
that there really are
a few good people left in the world.
I know you're hiding something
from me. I can tell.
No, I'm not.
Don't make me act harshly,
Miss Baxter, because you know I can.
You must do as you think best,
Mr Barrow,
just as I must.
Oh, whoo!
I have to thank you, Mr Molesley.
Oh? Why's that?
There are things in my past
that have made me afraid
but...
I'm not afraid any more.
I'm not sure what will happen
but whatever it is,
it's better than being afraid.
You've made me strong, Mr Molesley.
Your strength has made me strong.
My what?
What time do you go tomorrow?
The train leaves at ten.
I reckon Spain and Italy may be
pretty hot,
so when you see me again -
No, no.
I won't be coming to America.
Don't make a decision too -
I'm not coming.
But thank you.
And please thank Mr Levinson.
You know why I asked you?
I think I do, yes.
I didn't say it because I thought
it might frighten you off.
But we could make a go of it.
Daisy? I suspect
we want different things, Mr Slade.
But it means that much to me
to hear you say it. Thank you.
Could I try? Try what?
To cook for Mr Levinson. I know all
the dishes Daisy makes, I promise.
Yes, but it would have worked
with Daisy in New York -
If Mr Levinson likes her style
of cooking...
Please. Give me a trial.
I'll save up and pay my own way out
if I have to.
Let her come! You've told him
you've got an English cook
and he won't know the difference.
OK. I'll cable
when I get back to New York
and you won't have to pay
for your ticket.
But I warn you -
he can be quite picky.
Don't worry. This is my chance.
I swear I won't let you down.
That were kind of you, Daisy.
Why shouldn't she go to America
if it's what she wants?
You're not upset, then,
by Mr Slade making advances?
Upset?
Mrs Patmore,
if you knew what it feels like
to have a young man keen
to court me...
I'd kiss him if it wouldn't give him
the wrong idea.
Upset? I'm that chuffed,
it'll take me through
to next summer.
Did I ever tell you how glad
they were to get that coat
for the Russian refugees?
Poor souls.
I just wish you'd let me go through
the pockets first, that's all.
I'm sorry.
Is there anything I can do
to make up for it?
Mmm.
Let me think.
You could always buy me a penny lick.
(GASPS)
Come on - I dare you.
But if get my trousers wet...
If you get them wet, we'll dry them.
Suppose I fall over?
Suppose a bomb goes off,
suppose we're hit by a falling star?
You can hold my hand,
then we'll both go in together.
I think I will hold your hand.
It'll make me feel a bit steadier.
You can always hold my hand
if you need to feel steady.
I don't know how but you managed
to make that sound a little risque.
And if I did?
We're getting on, Mr Carson,
you and I.
We can afford to live a little.